My name is Kevin Javier and I was born here
in Italy and my parents are of Filipino origin.
My name is Anastasio Moten. I was born in Parma...
...province of Padua, in a small town called Ponso.
I am of Indian origin. At noon, I cook a bit of
Italian food. For dinner we eat Indian food.
...sweet polenta, polenta with rabbit, polenta with braised meat. I mean, on Sunday, polenta is typical of Bergamo, right?
I feel Italian, even though I don't have citizenship, but the simple fact is that I've been here since I was three years old.
So if I don't feel Italian, what should I feel like?
I'm on the bus, maybe I'm talking to a friend of mine, to someone, maybe on the phone, after a while they turn around.
“Ah but... oh wow... you're black?”
The compliment that I get  is, “Oh, you speak
Italian so well!” And I reply, “You, too!”
Since I'm not an Italian citizen, I should always have these things with me: my residence permit, issued on June 27, 2008.
It expires on October 29, 2010 and it arrived to me in August
of 2010. I could basically take this one and throw it away.
And I have to walk around with this, which is the postal receipt, the classic receipt of registered letters of postal packages.
It's a bulletin. I have to walk around with these,
a substitute for a residence permit.
If I don't always have these, I risk being taken to
the police station and maybe being put in a cell.
When I say “I have a residence permit,” people are amazed
and they say to me “Why?” like, “Don't you have citizenship?”
I am still not an Italian citizen. I understood this
whole thing about citizenship in the ninth grade.
I had the opportunity to participate in a selection for Nationals.
Even if they chose me, I couldn't be part
of it for the mere fact that I'm not Italian.
At 18, I would have liked to do service, enroll in the army and go somewhere, but unfortunately I couldn't  and I still can't.
It says, “Born at Nigeria.” In correct Italian,
however, it should be “Born IN Nigeria,”
and anyway I wasn't born in Nigeria, I was born in Rome.